迈克 · 诺斯: 在这个工作坊里，我们最不想做的就是
&gt;&gt; Mike North: The last thing we're
gonna do in this workshop is to give
编译器如何看待你的代码。
you an idea of how the TypeScript
compiler sees your code.
我们将通过一个非常快速的
And we're gonna do this through
taking a tour of a really quick and
肮脏的文件产生器。
dirty documentation generator.
它充分利用了编译器收集的所有信息
That takes advantage of all of the
information that compiler gathers as it
解析和输入检查你的打字稿源代码。
parses and
type checks your TypeScript source code.
让我们来看看第九个注释部分，编译器 API。
So let's look at in the notes section
at number nine, Compiler API.
Mike North: 首先，这证明了我一直在使用 isDefined over 和
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So first, this is proof
that I keep using isDefined over and
再来一次。
over again.
没有它我好像过不下去。
I just cannot seem to get by without it.
我们要进口，这被称为外卡进口。
We're going to import,
this is called a wild card import.
我们只是从打字稿和打字稿模块中获得了一些东西。
We're just sort of getting everything from
TypeScript, from the TypeScript module.
我们可以从打字稿中导入 createProgram,
We could do import
createProgram from TypeScript,
然后我们可以直接使用 createProgram。
and then we'd be able to
use createProgram directly.
它所做的一切就是让我们可以做。
All this does is it allows
us to do ts.createProgram.
迈克 · 诺斯: 在那儿。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: There it is.
这只是因为我们需要一大堆不同的东西
And this is just because we need
a whole bunch of different stuff, but
这有点微妙。
it's a little nuanced.
这有点像打字稿。
It's kinda TypeScript specific.
你在 JavaScript 中看不到通配符导入。
You don't see wildcard
imports in JavaScript.
迈克 · 诺斯: 我们要做的第一件事,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So
the first thing we're gonna do,
我们要创建一个打字稿程序。
we're going to create
a TypeScript program.
我们传递了两个信息。
And we're passing in two things.
这里的第一个对象选项,
This first object here, options,
它在概念上等同于 ts.Config 编译器选项。
it is equivalent conceptually to
your ts.Config compiler options.
所以我们有目标，我们可以有模块和
So we've got target,
we could have module and
例如，ModuleKind，CommonJS，任何我们想放入的东西。
say ys.ModuleKind.CommonJS,
whatever we want to put in there.
这些对应于我们当时看到的一些命令行标志
These correspond to some of the command
line flags we were looking at when we
首先使用 TypeScript 编译器进行编译，这也是 ts. Config 中的内容。
first played with TypeScript compiler and
it's also what's in ts.Config.
我们必须传递的第二个东西是 rootNames。
The second thing we
must pass is rootNames.
我所做的就是使用节点路径模块，我把它们连接在一起
And so what I've done is using nodes
path module, I've joined together
一个适当的路径，导致我们编译的例子，在第一件事
an appropriate path that leads to the
example we compiled in that first thing
我们做的就像我们四处打探如何将打字稿转换成 JavaScript 一样。
we did as we were poking around with
how to turn TypeScript into JavaScript.
所以它指向 ts 文件。
So it's pointing to the ts file.
接下来我们要做的就是抓住这个
The next thing we're gonna do is grab this
当我们到达这行代码的时候，它将被编译和
program, and by the time we reach this
line of code it will be compiled and
检查完毕，准备出发。
type checked and ready to go.
我们要拿到所有的源文件
We're gonna get all of
the source files and
过滤掉那些声明文件。
filter out those that
are declaration files.
这是一个很好的机会
And this is a good opportunity for
我来给你们展示一下程序自动输入的内容。
me to kinda show you what all is brought
in automatically to you program.
因此，我将暂时将其注释掉，console.log (nonDeclFiles)。
So I'll comment that out temporarily,
console.log(nonDeclFiles).
我们现在就调用这些文件，因为我们要跳过过滤
Let's just call that files now since
we're gonna skip the filtering
为了日志的目的我要把它们转换成,
and for the purposes of logging,
I'm just gonna transform them,
我只需要路径名。
their objects, and
I just want the path name.
所以我想运行这个代码。
So I wanna run this code.
迈克 · 诺斯: 所以我没有存钱。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So I didn't save.
我的错。
My bad.
我们有很多不同的东西。
And we have a whole lot
of different stuff.
以前有人用过打字稿。
Someone has used TypeScript before.
你能告诉我这些文件是关于什么的吗？
Can you tell me what these
files are all about?
说话人1: 这里有各种不同库的类型定义。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: There type definitions for
various different libraries.
迈克 · 诺斯: 节点，对吗？
&gt;&gt; Mike North: For node, right?
任何以@类型开头的东西都是来自肯定输入的,
Anything that starts with @types,
those are from the definitely typed,
公共类型定义的主回购。
master repo of public type definitions.
你可以通过点击
You could get to those
by just clicking into
我从各个节点模块导入的内容。
stuff that I'm importing from
the various node modules.
在类型节点路径，对，所以这些都是不同的节点模块。
At types node path, right, so
these are all the different node modules.
所以让我们继续看看这里。
So let's keep looking around here.
还有一些更多类型的节点，很多很多。
There's some more types nodes stuff,
lots and lots of it.
迈克 · 诺斯: 只是扫描看看什么时候事情看起来有点不同。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: And just scanning for
when things look a bit different.
这是摩卡和印度茶，所以我用它们来做测试。
Here's mocha and chai, so
I'm using those for testing.
好的，最后我们有了 hello-ts 中的原始源文件。
Okay, finally we have the original
source file in hello-ts.
请注意，其他所有内容都是 d.ts 文件。
Note that everything else
has been a d.ts file.
这些只是正在导入的声明文件。
These are just declaration
files that are being imported.
然后在下面，因为这是从第一次打印出来的
And then underneath,
because this is printed from the first
一直被解析到最后的东西。
things that are parsed all
the way to the last things.
比如，我失去了我的位置，所以这里是程序。
Like, I lost my place,
so here's the program.
这就是我认为的源代码。
This is what I would
consider my source code.
下面是 esnext 对吧,
Underneath that we've got esnext, right,
这些实际上是打字稿本身附带的声明文件。
these are actually declaration files
that come with TypeScript itself.
这就是我可以点击的地方，例如，什么是一个好例子？
So that's where I can click on
something like, what's a good example?
地图，排列，地图。
Map, array.map.
是编程语言的一部分，对吧？
Part of the programming language, right?
我们在一个声明文件里找到了自己,
Well we find ourself
in a declaration file,
所以他的机制是用来消费类型库
so he same mechanism that is
used to consume library type
使用类型信息
information is used to consume
the type information for
所有我们认为是 JavaScript 的东西。
everything we would consider JavaScript.
Dom API 也是如此。
Same goes with the dom API.
如果我们看看这里，实际上有几个不同的版本。
And if we looked here, there are actually
a couple different versions of these.
当我们说，我想针对 es17或2017或
Where, when we're saying,
I want to target es17 or 2017 or
2016年或者2015年，你只是选择了一个不同的文件。
2016 or 2015, you just end up kind
of picking a different file here.
很多新的只是堆叠在旧的上面,
And a lot of the new one just
stack on top of the old ones,
因为很自然的，语言就像时间的敌人。
cuz naturally,
the language is additive as time foes on.
所以如果我们要构建文档引擎
So If we're gonna build
the documentation engine
我们可能不想记录整个 JavaScript 编程语言。
we probably don't wanna document the whole
JavaScript programming language.
我们最后会碰到很多不同的东西。
We're gonna end up touching
on a lot of different things.
它开始变得非常大，非常快。
And it sort of starts to get very big,
very quickly.
所以当你触摸字符串的时候，它们都在字符串方法中
So as you touch the string,
now they are all in string methods and
它们指的是数组，还有数组方法。
those refer to arrays, and
there are the array methods.
某种程度上很快就会解体，变得巨大。
Sort of unravels very quickly and
becomes huge.
这就是为什么我要过滤
So that is why I'm filtering through for
只有那些不是声明文件的东西。
only those things that
are not declaration files.
只有 ts 文件，没有 d.ts 文件。
Only the ts files, not the d.ts files.
谢天谢地，这里有一个名为 isDeclarationFile 的属性。
And, thankfully, there is a property
on there called isDeclarationFile.
如果我现在也这么做,
If I were to do the same thing now,
日志 nonDeclFiles.map
console.log nonDeclFiles.map
文件名，再次运行它。
fileName, run it again.
好了，我们完成了一个。
There we go, we're done to one.
一个源文件，其他的都是有帮助的额外类型信息
One source file, everything else is
just extra type information that helps
一切都编译正确。
everything compile properly.